<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on chischaschos rocks</title>
    <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on chischaschos rocks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//chischaschos.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog City Ruby&#39;s Approaching a legacy application</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/fog-city-ruby-legacy-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/fog-city-ruby-legacy-apps/</guid>
      <description>Fog City Ruby&amp;rsquo;s Approaching a legacy application Exposed at Fog City Ruby on June 13, 2017.
This talk is my attempt on improving the original talk applying what I learned after two years condensed in 18 minutes.
Published in its own micro site at: https://chischaschos.github.io/approaching-legacy-systems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning window functions with postgresql</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/learning-window-functions-with-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 03:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/learning-window-functions-with-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>Objective Learn what window functions are and how they are used.
This example uses the fake messaging app playgroung. What we are going to do is to get the messages from groups a user is part of, only the top 3 messages of each group sorted by creation date are returned.
This blog is written using commit cf971929380a91730dffb9b87177f664bd87aa1a of the fake messaging app playground.
An example use case What we are going to do is to obtain the latest 3 messages a user has from each group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned from creating a postgresql data playground</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/lessons-learned-from-creating-a-postgresql-data-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/lessons-learned-from-creating-a-postgresql-data-playground/</guid>
      <description>Objective Create a script that produces a postgresql database. The structure will be fixed and the contents of the db may vary. The shape of the data should be mostly the same so that every time I rebuild the db I can expect similar queries across rebuilds to output similar data.
End result This world is built and feed with fake-messaging-app-pg. I expect to keep changing it but I can call the first iteration completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest to learn GraphQL</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/the-quest-to-learn-graphql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/the-quest-to-learn-graphql/</guid>
      <description>The Quest to learn GraphQL This is just a bunch of notes taken while learning about GraphQL.
What is graphql  http://graphql.org/ https://www.quora.com/What-problem-does-GraphQL-solve  There is graphql in different languages such as golang, nodejs and ruby among others.
 Ruby
 https://github.com/rmosolgo/graphql-ruby https://github.com/Shopify/graphql-batch  Nodejs
 Join Monster video Join Monster repo DataLoader   Who uses it?  Shopify Github Facebook  Performance Can we get a sense on how to measure it or what to expect?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging guard-jasmine error</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/debugging-guard-jasmine-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 11:11:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/debugging-guard-jasmine-error/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I&amp;rsquo;m working on a project that uses guard-jasmine (1.19.2). For a number reasons I can&amp;rsquo;t upgrade it yet.
This morning the test headless test suite started failing with:
➜ bundle exec guard-jasmine Guard::Jasmine starts Unicorn spec server on port 58583 in test environment (coverage off). Waiting for Jasmine test runner at http://localhost:58583/jasmine Run all Jasmine suites Run Jasmine suite at http://localhost:58583/jasmine 2016-09-27 22:01:55.025 phantomjs[3242:3209481] *** WARNING: Method userSpaceScaleFactor in class NSView is deprecated on 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferred learning resources around Software Development</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/preferred-learning-resources-around-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 08:39:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/preferred-learning-resources-around-software-development/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Share my preferences.
 Books
 Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby Agile Software Development, Principles, Patterns, and Practices Head First Object-Oriented Analysis and Design Clean Code The Clean Coder The Passionate Programmer The Senior Software Engineer Soft Skills Practical Vim Domain Driven Design Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture Head First Design Patterns Refactoring: Ruby Edition Working Effectively With Legacy Code  Practices
 exercism.io Coderetreats Code Katas Vim Adventures Vim Golf Learn touch typing Hacker Rank  Job Search</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Code Retreat</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/self-code-retreat-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 14:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/self-code-retreat-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to participate in many Coderetreats and I want to do a small coding practice that keeps the same feeling.
What is a Code retreat? The Coderetreat site says:
 Coderetreat is a day-long, intensive practice event, focusing on the fundamentals of software development and design.
 A Code retreat day is structured in two main parts:
Setting context  A previously chosen exercise is explained to the audience, most of the times the chosen exercise is Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resque and Sidekiq as of August 2016</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/resque-and-sidekiq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 07:53:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/resque-and-sidekiq/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Some months ago, at an interview I got asked this:
 What would you use resque or sidekiq and why?
 My answer was something along the lines of:
 Sidekiq consumes less memory, so that sounds better. Both Resque and Sidekiq are stable and widely used in production. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Resque in a 3 applications, two of them are still running and processing tons of background jobs. Before making my choice I would need to know the kind of background processing that we would do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail inc</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/fail-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 05:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/fail-inc/</guid>
      <description> Fail inc  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WDT&#39;s Four Phases Tests</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/four-phases-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/four-phases-test/</guid>
      <description> WDT&amp;rsquo;s Four Phases Tests A talk about Four-Phase Test for Web Dev Talks Mexico (WDT).
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSpec and the Four Phase Tests</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/rspec-antipatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 20:49:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/rspec-antipatterns/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I want to know what are the best practices to write RSpec tests when striving for a Four Phase Test.
What the internet says about it?  https://thoughtbot.com/upcase/videos/four-phases-of-testing. https://robots.thoughtbot.com/how-we-test-rails-applications http://code.tutsplus.com/articles/rspec-testing-for-beginners-part-1--cms-26716 http://www.justinweiss.com/articles/writing-better-tests-with-the-three-phase-pattern/  Notes  let may be lazy and convenient. If another developer comes and looks at the it, he will see a mystery guest. You create a DSL within RSpec, DSL puzzle. Each piece of indirection improves high level view, but makes it more complex when you have to change it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WDT&#39;s Approaching a legacy application</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/wdt-legacy-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 21:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/wdt-legacy-apps/</guid>
      <description> WDT&amp;rsquo;s Approaching a legacy application Another talk for Web Dev Talks Mexico (WDT).
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Magma Rails&#39;s Object Oriented Design and Patterns</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/object-oriented-design-and-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/object-oriented-design-and-patterns/</guid>
      <description> 2011 Magma Rails Conference&amp;rsquo;s Object Oriented Design and Patterns  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WDT&#39;s Sinatra: De nada a TODO</title>
      <link>//chischaschos.github.io/post/sinatra-todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chischaschos.github.io/post/sinatra-todo/</guid>
      <description> WDT&amp;rsquo;s Sinatra: De nada a TODO A talk for Web Dev Talks Mexico (WDT).
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>